PHILIP MAMMEN Featured

Supervisor seeking roles in Logistics Operations, Warehouse Operations, Vendor Management, Transport Management, Inventory Management, Supply Chain Management, Sourcing Management, Procurement Management, Strategic Planning, Cost Reduction, SAP.



Current Location: abu dhabi Total Experience: 27 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Delhi / NCR, Mumbai Highest Degree: BeC [Economics]

Functional Area: Purchase / Logistics / Supply Chain

Role: Logistics Mgr

Industry: Auto/Auto Ancillary

Key Skills: Supervisor, Logistics Manager, Logistics Operations, Warehouse Operations, Vendor Management, Transport

Management, Inventory Management, Supply Chain Management, Sourcing Management, Procurement

Management, Strategic Planning, Cost Reduction, SAP.

Last Active: 5-Apr-21 Last Modified: 5-Apr-21

Summary

Warehousing & Logistics Professional with experience of nearly 19 years in Logistics Management, Stores / Inventory Management, Dispatch Department, Vendor Development, Client relationship Management and People Management; currently associated with Al Masaood Automobiles as Supervisor - Warehouse Operations & Logistics: Nissan Central Parts Department - Warehouse, Abu Dhabi. Drove warehouse and logistics operations in Nissan Central Parts warehouse by developing and driving outsourcing strategies, focusing on identification, evaluation, selection, negotiation, and. Increased stock accuracy and reduced order shortages by improving goods-in and cycle counting processes. Expertise in sourcing goods, equipment, services and managing vendors in a time & cost-effective manner. Successfully operate HSE procedures in main parts distribution center and all branch warehouses according to the company's HSE policy

Work Experience

Al Masaood Automobiles as Supervisor - Warehouse Operations & Logistics Nissan Central Parts Department - Warehouse May 2015 to Dec 2020

Key Result Areas:

Leading a team of over 80 members and managing logistics & warehouses for distribution of goods to the final customers; negotiating and finalizing contracts of freight rates for primary, secondary distribution and 3PLs

Overseeing of Off Shore coordination with overseas stations with contacting shipper to On Shore operations/documentation & delivery in regard to Air, Sea & Road freights

Playing a key role in warehousing budget, suggests and implements improvements, repairs and investments Managing overall scrapping of goods process in order to ensure compliance with the company's procedure Scheduling and overseeing Warehouse Team to meet the demands of the fulfillment center and managing the flow and quality of work to maximize efficiency and minimize overtime

Developing alternate vendor base to achieve cost reduction, increase revenues, streamline process workflow and enhance productivity innovatively for in-house and vendor's parts

Ensuring all aspects of received parts orders are complete and accurate, focusing on accurate documentation, physical checks and complete 'receipt'/ entry into Autoline system

Maintaining staff safety and complying with QHSE policy

Checking supply trip schedule, review vehicle trip logs, vehicle service schedules including fuel and other consumables expense report

Integrating logistics with customer sales, order management, accounting & shipping departments; analyzing financial impact of changes such as routing, shipping modes, product volumes, mixes and carriers

Driving Continuous Process Improvement (CPI) process by managing and directing supply chain scorecard for the region; monitoring regions performance by highlighting progress and areas to improve

Reviewing insurance claims and processes on transit damage, parts defective/missing/damaged on both ocean freight and DHL

MTM Marine LLC as Sales/ Procurement/ Supply Chain Coordinator Mar 1997 to Mar 2015

Key Result Areas:

Expedited sales orders, liaised for goods, logistics and operations to ensure deliveries were on schedule

Reviewed shipping documents and issued invoices and other pertinent system for all customer orders relating to spare, repair parts and services

Tracking and reporting key procurement strategies including cost analysis to demonstrate reduction of expenses and improvement of overall productivity

Acquired requisitions, items/ services for the operation, grant purchase orders to preferred suppliers and resolved problems with supply orders

Coordinated with project segment managers and contract administrators, buyers, expeditors, inspectors, materials controllers, transportation and logistics and other parties as required

Universal Trading Co. as Asst. Administrator - Product Registration & Compliance (PRC) Jan 1992 to Mar 1995

Key Result Areas:

Create and maintain accurate files, reports and registration dossiers for registration purposes

Handle communications with the agencies (brands) to obtain the visibility of the new product list, gathering and reviewing the registration documents in accordance with the authorities' guidelines and regulations.

Maintain an accurate trackers and archives for registration records.

Prepare and maintain periodic reports on the registration progress.

Submission of the registration dossiers and follow up on the registration status with the operations team and authorities when necessary.

Support preparation of new group visa applications for special projects in joint venture with Voltas International Ltd., Abu Dhabi.

Document control, prepare staff overtimes, HR staff support activities and process commercial licenses renewals.

Education

UG: BeC (Economics) from Kerala University, India in 1991

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Training in Leadership Development Course

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
SAP		

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Arabic				
Hindi				
Malayalam				

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time